在上一集里
Previously on Transformers Prime:
可怕的风暴让当地人目瞪口呆
Freak storms unlike any the region has seen
海啸使加拿大沿岸岌岌可危
tsunamis threaten the Canadian coast
雷暴也在戈壁滩上肆虐横行
while lightning storms pummel the Gobi Desert.
恐怕 地核并不是由岩浆组成的
I fear that the Earth's very core is not comprised of magma
而是黑暗能量
but of Dark Energon.
看在火种源的份上…
By the allspark...
塞博特恩人的心跳？
Cybertronian heartbeat?
你的意思是 地底下有个活物
You mean something's living down there
就在地球里边？
inside our planet?
是“宇宙大帝” 远古的恶魔
Unicron, an ancient evil
他的血液在石化之后 形成了我们所说的那种黑暗能量…
whose fossilized blood comprises the matter which we call Dark Energon...
痴人说梦！
Pride for fool.
我无需一个下人插手此事
I have no need of your lowly assistance.
擎天柱 我发现宇宙大帝火种的活性急剧增强
I'm detecting a swell of Unicron's spark activity.
现在 称我为宇宙大帝――你的毁灭者！
Now know me as Unicron, your destroyer!
擎天柱 你发现宇宙大帝苏醒的其他迹象了吗？
Optimus, have you uncovered any further sign of Unicron's emergence?
宇宙大帝是力量的化身
Unicron is power incarnate
而你 最后一个领袖
and you, the last of the Primes
将步向死亡！
shall perish.
看来回答是肯定的
I take that as a yes.
我们这就出发！
We are on our way.
不行
Negative.
单靠蛮力是无法打倒宇宙大帝的
Unicron cannot be defeated by sheer force.
他要的是我 救护车
He wants me, Ratchet.
这场战斗必须由我独自面对
This fight must be mine alone.
难道救护车没有传达我的命令吗？
Did Ratchet not relay my command?
返回基地
Return to base.
援兵也挽回不了你即将毁灭的下场
Reinforcements will not prevent your destruction
原始天尊的门徒
disciple of Primus.
擎天柱 宇宙大帝的目标是你
Optimus, you are Unicron's target
也许你才应该返回基地
maybe you should consider returning to the base.
在宇宙大帝的化身面前 地球上没有任何藏身之处
These manifestations of Unicron can locate me anywhere on Earth
即使是基地的屏障 也只能在短时间内隐藏我的位置
even our base's shielding will only cloak my position for so long.
我不能让其他人身处险境
I will not put others at risk.
那就撤退 我们来开路
Then fall back and let us take the lead
就这一次
just this once.
请理智一点吧
Please listen to reason.
万一你牺牲了 擎天柱
If you don't survive, Optimus
恐怕这星球也活不成了
I fear neither will this planet.
那好吧
Very well.
我们走！
Let's move.
不 这不是宇宙大帝的真身
No, not Unicron himself
只是他的另一个化身而已
but another of his manifestations.
既然我们打不过宇宙大帝
If we can't beat Unicron
而且跑也跑不过他
and we can't out run him.
我们到底该怎么办？
What exactly are we supposed to do?
我们所能做的…
All we can do...
只有尽快消灭这些傀儡
neutralize his vassals as they appear
直到找出办法 既能消灭他 又不必毁掉我们脚下的这颗星球
until we find a way to destroy him without destroying the very Earth upon which we walk.
愚蠢
Fool.
我就是这个世界的过去 也是它的将来
I am this world's past, and its future
鉴于目前的状况…
and as of this moment...
不！
No!
所有的领袖都将成为历史
All Primes are simply past.
不是我
Wasn't me.
也不是我
Me neither.
救护车？
Ratchet?
怎么了？是谁干的？
What is it? What happened?
是我干的
I happened.
威震天！
Megatron!
金刚虎王也来了？
King Kong's there, too?
他已经投靠了宇宙大帝
He has aligned himself with Unicron.
别这么肯定
Don't be so sure.
威震天刚刚救了擎天柱的命
Megatron just saved Optimus' tailpipe.
真是出乎意料 你我上次还刀兵相见
It is rather ironic considering our last encounter.
如果没记错 你当时无论如何都要熄灭我的火种
If my memory serves, you were desperately attempting to extinguish my spark.
那是我一贯的想法
That option remains very much in play.
我也不指望你心慈手软
I would expect nothing less.
不过 我有个提议
However, I have a proposal.
和我联手 打败我们共同的敌人
Join me in defeating our shared enemy
宇宙大帝 混沌制造者
Unicron, the Chaos Bringer.
哈！荒唐！
Ha! Absurd.
宇宙大帝是邪恶的化身
Unicron is evil incarnate.
如果威震天要选择阵营的话
If Megatron was to take any side
干嘛要选我们这边？
why would it be ours?
因为威震天的尊严使他不能容忍 自己以外的任何人统治这个星球
Because Megatron's pride would never allow anyone other than himself to rule this planet.
你真是太了解我了 擎天柱
You know me all too well, Optimus.
你手下有一支虎头大军
You lead an army of Cons
还来找我们干嘛？
why come to us?
因为这次特殊行动 需要一种我驾驭不了的力量――
Because this particular endeavor requires something beyond the realm of my command--
领袖的力量
-- the power of a Prime.
哼 那看来我们用不着你了
Huh, then I guess we don't need you.
恰恰相反
On the contrary
擎天柱也许是唯一能击败宇宙大帝的人
Optimus maybe the only one who can defeat Unicron
但能带你们找到他的人 非我莫属
but I remain the only one who can guide you to him.
宇宙大帝的血液在我的体内流淌
Unicron's life blood runs through me
只有我能听到他的思想
only I can hear his thoughts
可以抢先一步采取行动
anticipate his movements.
擎天柱 我们过去的阵营
Optimus, our past alliances--
什么汽车人 霸天虎 都去他的吧
-- Autobot, Decepticon, no longer matter
眼下 宇宙大帝复活了
not while Unicron lives.
过去的事绝不能说算就算！
The past always matters!
汽车人与霸天虎之间的停战协议
A truce between Autobot and Decepticon.
你觉得 我们对它的信任度有多久？
How long do you expect us to believe that will last?
不过是维护共同的利益而已
Only as long is this mutually beneficial.
那么 等到这个共同目标达成之后呢？
And when our proposed to shared mission is complete?
我会征服这个星球…
I will conquer this Earth
用我的方式
my way.
霸天虎也会掏心窝子？
Brutal honesty from a Decepticon?
和小喽罗结盟 同样等于投靠大魔王！
Aligning with the lesser of two evils is still siding with evil.
你们以为自己见识过宇宙大帝的全力吗？
Do you think you've witnessed the full power of Unicron?
那几个步兵连塞牙缝都不够
Those foot soldiers were nothing more than a taste.
宇宙大帝还没有完全苏醒
Unicron has yet to fully awaken.
时间每过一分钟 混沌使者都会愈加强大
With each passing moment, the bringer of chaos evolves
把地球搅得天翻地覆
mutating Earth from the inside out.
我们目前所见的 不过是个序幕
What we have witnessed until now is but a prelude
他的觉醒将给你们的世界带来无尽的浩劫
of the utter devastation his rising will wreak upon your world.
就像你为了追求权力 毁掉塞博特恩那样？
Like your quest for power destroyed Cybertron?
别搞错了
Make no mistake.
这一次 肯定会有一颗星球留给我统治
This time there will be a planet left for me to rule.
即使我们同意
Even if we agree
可宇宙大帝身处在地球的中心
Unicron is all the way down at the center of the Earth.
我们要怎么下去？开车吗？
How are we supposed to get there? Drive?
只有一条路
There is only one way.
绝对不行！
Absolutely not!
传送到太空 或是行进中的列车上 已经够困难了！
Ground bridging into space or onto moving train is difficult enough
这次居然要漫无目的地传送到 一个智慧生命体内部？
but plotting a blind jump inside of a sentient being?
更何况 直接暴露在那么多的黑暗能量下 会让你们浑身无力
Besides, direct expose to that much Dark Energon will debilitate you.
你们可没有威震天那种免疫力
You haven't built up immunity like Megatron has.
这正是我们联手的另一个好处：
Yet another strong argument for solidarity
我可以当向导
my guidance.
你能提供宇宙大帝精确的坐标吗？
You can provide Unicron's exact coordinates?
如果你能把我们传送到星球的核心
If you transport us to this planet's core
我就能直接带你们找到宇宙大帝的火种
I can lead you directly to Unicron's spark
那可是黑暗力量的心脏！
the very heart of his darkness.
擎天柱 即使我们在传送后能活下来
Optimus, even if we survive the jump
又该怎么阻止宇宙大帝呢？
how are we supposed to stop Unicron?
用领导模块
With the Matrix of Leadership.
那是什么？
What is that?
一个装有纯粹能量的容器
A vessel of pure energy
历届领袖智慧的结晶
the collective wisdom of the Primes.
我们还有寻宝的时间吗？
Do we have time for a scavenger hunt?
我是说 擎天柱该去哪儿找这个“模块”呢？
I mean where is Optimus supposed to find this Matrix?
擎天柱不需要寻找
Optimus does not need to find it.
他一直把它带在身上
He carries it within him.
很久以前 领袖们依靠这种融合的力量 才战胜了宇宙大帝
It was the combined power of the Primes that defeated Unicron so long ago
这也是他现在想要摧毁你的原因
the very reason he now seeks to destroy you.
照这么说 将领导模块的力量 直接灌进宇宙大帝的火种
It would follow that unleashing the power of the Matrix directly into Unicron's spark
就可以让他重新长眠
would return him to stasis.
等等
Hold on.
如果一切都顺利进行的话
If everything goes right
宇宙大帝就会一直待在地下喽？
Unicron's gonna stay down there?
是啊 能不能…想办法把他除掉？
Yeah, can we sent them out somehow?
他不是住在地核里 杰克
He is not in the Earth's core, Jack.
他就是地核
He is the Earth's core.
拉斐尔说的对
Rafael is correct.
扰动地核可能会影响磁极
Tempering with your core could affect the magnetic poles
反而引发一些我们本该避免的特大灾难
trigger the very cataclysmic events we are attempting to remedy.
可惜的是 宇宙大帝正是你们星球的起源
Tragically, Unicron is your planet's very seed
从古至今 直到遥远的将来
always has been and always must be.
又来了一个
We got another one.
救护车 打开环陆桥
Ratchet, set the GroundBridge.
等等 我们就这么打开一条直通基地的大道 让威震天看热闹？
Wait, we're opening up a direct path into our base with Megatron standing right there?
说真的
And seriously
他真能拼了他的火种 给我们擦屁股吗？
he's gonna risk his own spark to save us?
哈哈哈 的确不是我的本性！
Haha... hardly my nature.
考虑一下我的提议
Consider my offer.
我来拖住它
I shall keep it busy.
还没有威震天陛下的消息吗?
No word yet from Lord Megatron?
看来统帅弃我们而去了 把我们扔在这个混乱的世界
It appears our leader has abandoned us while this world erupts in chaos.
我认为 我们必须做出长远的打算 无需考虑威震天了
I believe we must consider the possibility of the future without Megatron.
我知道 紧要关头需要采取非常措施
I know the desperate times call for desperate measures
可你真要放威震天进来吗？
but bringing Megatron here?
怎么能让那怪物靠近孩子们 你忘了他差点害死拉夫吗？
How can you even think about letting that monster near these children after what he did to Raf?
我们会严密监视他
He will be closely monitored
并且仅仅让他逗留到带我们上路为止
and only allowed to linger long enough to send us on our journey
一刻也不多留
not one moment more.
那家伙难道不会呼叫空袭吗？反正他知道你的位置
What's gonna stop the Con from calling in air strike could be he knows where you live?
我们用环陆桥带威震天进来
By ground bridging Megatron here
他无法确认我们的具体坐标
he will be unable to get a fix on our coordinates.
擎天柱 到时你会怎么样？我是说 模块能量释放之后
Optimus, what's gonna happen to you when all your... Matrix energy's released?
模块中的力量 从未以这种方式被使用过
The power within the Matrix has not previously been utilized in this particular manner.
但你总该知道个大概 对吧？
But you have an idea, don't you?
汽车人 为了拯救人类
Autobots, if humankind is to be saved
我没有选择 只能前进
I have no choice but to proceed
但你们可以选
but you do.
其实 我不了解人类
Well, I don't know about humankind
但我愿意这么做
but I'm willing to do it
就为神子
for Miko.
为杰克
For Jack.
威震天 我们这就接你过来
Megatron, we are sending transport.
你始终是个通情达理的人 擎天柱
You can always be relied upon to listen to reason, Optimus.
不公平！我还没见过他呢！
No fair! I've never seen him!
我们干嘛要藏起来？
Why do we have to hide?
因为我说了算
Because I said so.
看来 这就是大变活人的地方
So this is where the magic happens.
古色古香
Quaint.
- 拉夫！
- Raf!\N- Rafael, no!
你！
You!
啊 你看起来比上次见面时精神多了 小东西
Ah, you're looking much better than the last time we met, little one.
人类啊 真顽强
Humans, resiliant.
来吧 拉夫
Come on Raf.
他不值得你拼命
He isn't worth it.
还有你 我对面孔过目不忘 人类的也算上
And you, I never forget a face even that of a human.
你要是敢骗人
You double-cross anyone
我让你永远忘不了我这张脸 给我记住！
mine is the face you'll never forget, never!
救护车 从我们的客人那里接收目的地坐标
Ratchet, obtain the destination coordinates from our guest.
杰克
Jack
你能帮我保管一样东西吗？
will you keep something for me?
当然
Sure.
这是什么？
What is it?
这是…环陆桥电源的钥匙
It is the key to the GroundBridge power supply.
好吧 可这不该让救护车保管吗？
Ok, but shouldn't Ratchet have this?
或许吧
Perhaps
让我感到欣慰的是 你比我们最初见面时要更加成熟
but I've been impressed by how much you have matured since we first met.
因此
As such
我觉得 你完全可以担当保管这个重要器物的责任
I feel you've earned the responsibility of safeguarding this important device
直到我回来为止
until I return.
我不会让你失望的
I won't let you down.
目标锁定
Locked and ready.
你先
You first.
如你所愿
As you wish.
那个…宇宙大帝何时才会发现我们？
So how long before Unicron knows we're here?
别搞错了
Make no mistake.
他已经知道了
He already does.